Guide to the Nelson Peter Lewis papers, 1881-1942, 1896-1925 (bulk)
Lewis, Nelson Peter papers, 1881-1942, 1896-1925 (bulk)
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Nelson Peter Lewis papers, 1881-1942, 1896-1925 (bulk)
2712
Nelson Peter Lewis, 1856-1924
1 cubic ft.
Speeches, papers, scrapbooks, license, booklets, bound volumes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Speeches and papers given by Nelson P. Lewis; scrapbooks of news clippings and programs, 1896-1923; scrapbook of reviews of The Planning of the Modern City, 1919-1923; professional engineering license, 1921; three illuminated memorial booklets, 1924; copies of The Planning of the Modern City, 1916; Urbanizacion, the Spanish edition, 1917-1918; and other books by Nelson P. Lewis.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
City planner Nelson P. Lewis served as chief engineer of Brooklyn, New York from 1902-1920. He wrote The Planning of the Modern City, 1916. In May 1921 he became Director of the Physical Survey of the Regional Plan of New York and Its Environs.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Speeches and papers given by Nelson P. Lewis; scrapbooks of news clippings and programs, 1896-1923; scrapbook of reviews of The Planning of the Modern City, 1919-1923; professional engineering license, 1921; three illuminated memorial booklets, 1924; copies of The Planning of the Modern City, 1916; Urbanizacion, the Spanish edition, 1917-1918; and other books by Nelson P. Lewis.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lewis, Nelson Peter, 1856-1924.; Lewis, Nelson Peter, 1856-1924. Planning of the modern city.; Regional Plan of New York and Its Environs.
Subjects:
City planning.; City planners.; City planning--New York (N.Y.)--Brooklyn.
Places:
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Reviews.; Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Unbound papers
  - Notes, speeches, paper, 1899-1913 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Zoning Committee of the City of New York, minutes, 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Biographical material, condolence letters, resolutions, 1924, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Articles, 1904, 1920, 1922, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Speeches, 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Speeches, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Speeches, 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Speeches, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Speeches, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Speeches, 1911-1912 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Speeches, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Speeches, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Speeches, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Speeches, 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Speeches, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Speeches, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Portrait of Lewis (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Will (copy), Arthur Nelson, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Series II. Bound volumes
  - Scrapbook, 1907-1924, 1896-1909 (Box 2)
  - The Planning of the Modern City, 1916 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook of reviews, 1916-1923 (Box 2)
  - Three illuminated memorial resolutions, 1924 (Box 2)
  - Urbanizacion, Jose M. de Lasarte (Spanish translation of The Planning of the Modern City), 1917-1918 (Box 2)